Guide to the Hadley Family Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Hadley family papers
1729-1972
1839-1933
MS 985
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
47.08
(80 boxes)
Correspondence, writings, diaries, account books, and miscellanea of the Hadley family, including materials relating to James Hadley, 1821-1872, a professor of Greek at Yale University; Anne Loring Twining Hadley, 1816-1897, wife of James Hadley; Helen Harrison Morris Hadley, 1864-1939, wife of Arthur Twining Hadley, 1856-1930, president of Yale University, 1899-1921; and Morris Hadley, 1894-1979, the son of Arthur T. and Helen H. Hadley.
Hadley family
Hadley, Anne Loring Twining
Hadley, Arthur Twining, 1856-1930
Hadley, Helen Harrison Morris, 1864-1939
Hadley, James, 1821-1872
Hadley, Katherine Blodgett
Hadley, Morris, 1894-
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of the children of Mr. and Mrs. Arthur T. Hadley, 1938, Morris Hadley, 1942, Robin Hadley, 2008, and Elizabeth H. Hadley, 2012.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
The Hadley Family Papers is a collection of personal, professional and family materials concerning three generations of the Hadley family of New Haven, Conn.
The collection consists mainly of James Hadley's professional writings, Hadley household account books, and memorabilia; there is only a small amount of correspondence.
The chief figure in the collection is James Hadley, professor of Greek at Yale. His papers include a variety of personal and professional writings and notes. A manuscript diary covers, sporadically, part of the period Hadley spent in graduate study, his early career as a member of the Yale faculty, and his courtship and marriage. The diary is, for the most part, a detailed record of his daily life at Yale, and of the conversations and personalities around him. Yale Press published an edition of the diary in 1951; a typescript prepared for the publication by Hadley's granddaughter, Laura (Hadley) Moseley, is also in the collection.
Most of the James Hadley correspondence consists of letters and drafts written by him. Several letters and memoranda concern the affairs of Yale College. Other letters discuss matters of linguistics, philology, and publications; correspondents include Theodore D. Woolsey, Edmund Clarence Stedman, William W. Goodwin, and New Haven Mayor William Fitch. The letters show Hadley as a concerned and conscientious teacher. Besides a couple of letters to students, there are seven addressed to parents, mostly on matters of discipline; one of these (1856 Apr 9) describes the Yale riot of Mar 10, and another (1858 Mar 23) discusses a shooting incident.
The decisions for college class disputes (in folders 9-11), even more than the letters, show Hadley the instructor at work. In his preface to Hadley's Essays Philological and Critical(1873), William D. Whitney explains that the decisions represent Hadley's opinions on particular questions, written out in preparation for the weekly Junior class disputes at which he presided. The topics, some of which were debated more than once over the years, include: "Do present circumstances [1848 Feb] render improbable the permanent existence of the Union?", "Are the abilities of the sexes equal?", "Was Brutus justifiable in killing Caesar?", "Should the right of suffrage be extended to our colored population?", "Do spectres or ghosts ever appear?", "Was Aaron Burr a traitor?", and "Are popular superstitions more favorable to the cultivation of poetry than enlightened opinions?" The decisions have been arranged chronologically; the earliest were written when Hadley was still a student, and a participant in the disputes. There are some rather cryptic memoranda, which may be preliminary drafts for essays or speeches rather than decisions.
The papers contain some of Hadley's professional writings, but these manuscripts and notes were left in considerable disarray at the time of his death, and some manuscripts and parts of manuscripts appear to be missing. Of the three books, only his Greek Grammar was published in his life-time. The Introduction to Roman Law was edited by Theodore D. Woolsey, and most of the other writings were gone over by William D. Whitney when he and Hadley's family were selecting the papers published in Essays Philological and Critical. Some of the papers bear Whitney's annotations, and they are arranged in accordance with his lists. The notes are arranged roughly by subject.
James Hadley's wife, Anne Loring (Twining) Hadley, is represented in the papers by a series of household account books, begun the year after her marriage and continued for more than forty years.
Arthur Twining Hadley, son of James and Anne Hadley, was president of Yale University from 1899 to 1921, and his papers are part of the Presidential Records in the Yale Archives (YRG 2-A-13). The Hadley Family Papers contain some materials concerning the death of Arthur Twining Hadley. These include letters to his widow, Helen Harrison (Morris) Hadley, from Charles Seymour and others, regarding the printing of Seymour's memorial address; letters from James R. Angell, George Parmly Day, and Andrew Keogh concerning the establishment of the Arthur Twining Hadley Memorial Fund for the University Library; and resolutions of sympathy adopted by organizations of which Hadley was a member.
Helen Hadley's papers also include a series of household account books, begun before her marriage; notes from a Sunday school course; and a scrapbook of printed memorabilia and photographs which she put together for her children, Morris, Hamilton, and Laura Hadley.
The papers conclude with two folders of World War I materials compiled by Morris Hadley while he was assigned to an Intelligence section in Germany beginning in December 1918. The bulk of the material is mimeographed copies of the Third Army's daily intelligence summaries. Other papers include manuscript and mimeographed reports and notes on food, coal, and other economic matters, and a copy of the army's rules for inhabitants of the occupied area.
Biographical / Historical
James Hadley: philologist; B.A., Yale, 1842; spent two years at the Yale Divinity School, 1844-1845; appointed tutor in Yale College in 1845, promoted to asst. prof. of Greek in 1848, in 1851 succeeded Theodore Dwight Woolsey, holding the chair of Greek until retirement.
Arthur Twining Hadley was born in New Haven, Connecticut, on April 23, 1856, the son of James Hadley, a professor of Greek at Yale. He graduated from Yale College, Class of 1876, studied at the University of Berlin, and returned to Yale in 1879 as a tutor. Interested in the history and science of railroad transportation, he was associate editor of the Railroad Gazette, and lectured on railroad administration at Yale, 1883-1886; was acting professor of political economy in the Sheffield Scientific School, 1890-1891, and chair of political economy, 1891-1899; and served as the first dean of the Graduate School, 1892-1895. He was president of Yale University from 1899 to 1921. Hadley died in 1930.
Morris Hadley (1894-1979), son of Arthur T. and Helen H. Hadley, graduated from Yale University, Class of 1916. He received his M.A., 1940, and LL.D. ,1963, from Yale and a LL.D., 1965, from the University of Nevada. In 1918, he was in charge of the Brigade School of Fire at Camp Devens, Massachusetts, having reached the rank of major in the United States Army. He joined the law firm of Milbank, Tweed, Hadley & McCloy in 1929. Hadley served on the Yale Corporation, 1940-1962; was deputy director of the Office of Facts and Figures in Washington, 1941-1942, was a trustee of the Russell Sage Foundation; and sat on the board of trustees of the Pierpont Morgan Library and the New York Public Library, serving the latter as president, 1943-1958.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged by name of Hadley family member, and therein by type of material.
Families; Home economics -- Accounting; Students; World War, 1914-1918 -- Communications; Account books; Diaries; Photographs; Scrapbooks; Clergy; Educators; Philologists; Hadley, Anne Loring Twining; Hadley, Arthur Twining, 1856-1930; Hadley, Helen Harrison Morris, 1864-1939; Hadley, James, 1821-1872; Hadley, Katherine Blodgett; Hadley, Morris, 1894-; Whitney, William Dwight, 1827-1894; Woolsey, Theodore Dwight, 1801-1889; Hadley family; Saturday Morning Club (New Haven, Conn.); Yale University -- Faculty; Yale University -- Students
- Inventory, 1803, 1839-1933; 3 linear feet (8 boxes)
  Arrangement
  The original inventory is arranged by name of Hadley family member, and therein by type of material.
  - Hadley, James
    - Diary
      - Manuscript, 1843, 1846, 1848-1852 (Box 1, Folder 1-2)
      - Typescript, 1843, 1848-1852 (Box 1, Folder 3-7)
    - Incoming correspondence, 1869, undated (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Outgoing correspondence, 1849-1871, undated (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Decisions for college class disputes, 1840-1842, 1847-1867, undated (Box 2, Folder 9-11)
      General
      See also: box 3, folder 27
    - Prayers, 1844-1850, undated (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - A Greek Grammar for Schools and Colleges
      - Manuscripts, [1860s?] (Box 2, Folder 13-18)
      - Manuscripts, [1860s?] (Box 3, Folder 19)
      - Fragments, [1860s?] (Box 3, Folder 20-22)
      - Printed copy, annotated, 1860 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Introduction to Roman Law, in Twelve Academical Lectures
      - Manuscripts, [1870s?] (Box 3, Folder 24)
      - Manuscripts, outlines, fragments, notes, [1870s?] (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - Essays Philological and Critical: Selected from the Papers of James Hadley, papers edited by others, with a preface by William Dwight Whitney, 1847-1873 (Box 3, Folder 26-27)
    - Published articles, 1861-1872 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Unpublished articles, 1846-1871, undated (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - Miscellaneous papers, 1867-1872, undated (Box 4, Folder 30)
    - Miscellaneous writings, undated (Box 4, Folder 31)
    - Notes on philology and various languages and texts, 1803, 1840-1844, undated (Box 4, Folder 32)
    - Notes on Greek texts, [1847?], undated (Box 4, Folder 33)
    - Notes on mathematics, 1839-1844, undated (Box 5, Folder 34)
    - Miscellaneous notes and memorabilia, 1841-1866, undated (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - Hadley, Anne Loring Twining (Mrs. James)
    - Copper plate for engraved invitations, 1881 (Box 5, Folder 36)
    - Account books, 1852-1893 (Box 5, Folder 36-38)
  - Hadley, Helen Harrison Morris (Mrs. Arthur T.)
    - Account books, 1886-1889, 1892-1904 (Box 5, Folder 39)
    - Account books, 1905-1927 (Box 6, Folder 40-41)
    - Notes from a Sunday school course, Center Church, New Haven, Circa 1888-1891 (Box 6, Folder 42)
    - Scrapbook of greeting cards, colored pictures, and photographs, [ca. 1897-1904] (Box 7, Folder 43)
    - Incoming correspondence, 1903-1933, undated (Box 8, Folder 44)
    - Resolutions upon the death of Arthur T. Hadley, 1930 (Box 8, Folder 45-46)
  - Hadley, Morris
    - Mimeographed intelligence summaries, and manuscript and mimeographed reports and notes, 1918-1919, undated (Box 8, Folder 47-48)
- Additional material, 1770-1972 (inclusive), 1870-1930 (bulk); Accession 2009-M-036
  The accession is arranged by generation within the Hadley family, begining with James Hadley and ending with Morris Hadley and his wife, Katherine Blodgett Hadley.
  Scope and Contents
  The accession documents the personal lives of the family members. James Hadley and his wife, Anne Loring Twining, are primarily represented through correspondence. The personal correspondence of Arthur Twining Hadley was probably maintained by Yale University staff while he was president and is routine in nature, documenting organizational memberships, house matters, speaking invitations, and social events. There are twenty-two folders of his writings; it is unknown which of them were published.
  Helen Morris Hadley, wife of Arthur Twining Hadley, wrote papers for the New Haven Saturday Morning Club. Club members, all women, researched and wrote on various topics of interest. The topics of Helen's papers range from social customs in Berlin and New Haven; family travels; and interesting individuals she met; to life on the family farm in Newtown, Connecticut (Snake Rock Farm). Her incoming correspondence primarily concerns her social life, but there are letters from friends and Yale students discussing the outbreak of World War I. Her outgoing correspondence, in handwriting that is difficult to decipher, mostly concerns her children and family life.
  Morris Hadley, son of Arthur and Helen, attended Groton, Yale University, and Harvard University Law School, after which he fought in World War I. His outgoing correspondence provides an in-depth look at his daily life at the three educational institutions, including his experiences at military instruction camps while at Yale. He also wrote at length about his experiences in the Army during World War I, although he did not reach the front until ten days before the war ended. Correspondence between Morris and Katherine Blodgett prior to their marriage in 1919 provides an intimate portrait of their courtship.
  The Hadley Family photograph albums, which sometimes include memorabilia in the form of poems, sketches, and school report cards, primarily document life at family homes, travels, and social activities.
  - Hadley, James
    - Account book (continued by Arthur T. Hadley), 1852-1892 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, incoming
      - Hadley, Anne Loring Twining (Mrs. James), 1852-1861 (Box 1, Folder 2)
      - Hadley, Henry Hamilton (brother of James Hadley), 1856-1864 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence, outgoing
      - Hadley, Anne Loring Twining (Mrs. James), 1849-1861 (Box 1, Folder 4-5)
      - Yale Corporation, Circa 1871 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Photographs, Circa 1840s-1860s (Box 1, Folder 7-8)
    - Publishing contracts, 1860-1924 (Box 1, Folder 9-11)
  - Hadley, Anne Loring Twining (Mrs. James)
    - Correspondence, incoming
      - General, 1884-1894 (Box 1, Folder 12)
      - Twining, Mary (sister of Anne Loring Twining Hadley ), 1877-1879 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence, outgoing
      - Hadley, Arthur T. (son of Anne Loring Twining Hadley), 1878-1890 (Box 1, Folder 14-15)
      - Twining, Mary (sister of Anne Loring Twining Hadley ), 1877-1879 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Notebooks, 1877-1884 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Photograph, Circa 1870s (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Twining, Julia (sister of Anne Loring Twining Hadley ), Circa 1870s (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Hadley, Henry Hamilton (brother of James Hadley; one letter to "Mother"), 1856 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Hadley, Arthur T.
    - Authorizations to travel, United States government, 1903-1910 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Biographical, 1899-1928 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, Incoming
      - 1897-1930 (Box 3, Folder 2-4)
      - Undated (Box 3, Folder 5)
      - A-Y, 1898-1900 (Box 3, Folder 6-9)
      - A-Y, 1901-1902 (Box 4, Folder 1-4)
      - A-N, 1903-1904 (Box 4, Folder 5-7)
      - P-W, 1903-1904 (Box 5, Folder 1-2)
      - A-W, 1905 (Box 5, Folder 3-5)
      - A-R, 1906-1907 (Box 5, Folder 6-9)
      - S-W, 1906-1907 (Box 6, Folder 1)
      - A-W, 1908-1910 (Box 6, Folder 2-8)
      - A-Z, 1910-1914 (Box 7, Folder 1-7)
      - A-Z, 1915-1918 (Box 8, Folder 1-7)
      - A-J, 1918-1920 (Box 8, Folder 8-9)
      - K-Z, 1918-1920 (Box 9, Folder 1-2)
      - A-Z, 1920-1921 (Box 9, Folder 3-6)
      - A-D, 1921 (Box 9, Folder 7)
      - E-Y, 1921 (Box 10, Folder 1-4)
    - Correspondence, outgoing
      - 1908-1915 (Box 11, Folder 2)
        - Index, 1908-1915 (Box 11, Folder 1)
      - 1916-1921 (Box 12, Folder 2)
        - Index, 1916-1921 (Box 12, Folder 1)
      - Worcester, Edwin D., 1899-1915 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Engagement calendars, 1899-1923 (Box 13, Folder 2-7)
      - Additional material, 1922-1929 (Box 14, Folder 1-5)
    - Financial, 1892-1928 (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Library (notebook), 1876-1877 (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Obituaries, 1930 (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Phelps, William Lyon (notebook from Arthur T. Hadley course), 1888 (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Photographs, Circa 1860s-1920s (Box 15, Folder 1-4)
    - Publishing contracts, 1884-1934 (Box 16, Folder 1-2)
    - Railroad research materials, 1846, circa 1880s-1890s (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Teaching notebooks
      - 1879-1890s (Box 16, Folder 4-6)
      - 1880s-1890s (Box 17, Folder 1-5)
      - Notebooks, 1880s-1890 (Box 18, Folder 1-5)
    - Writings
      - Chronological
        - 1880s-1906 (Box 19, Folder 1-6)
        - 1921-1926, undated (Box 20, Folder 1-2)
      - Berlin lectures, English text, 1907-1908 (Box 20, Folder 3-4)
      - Berlin lectures, German text, 1907-1908 (Box 20, Folder 5-7)
      - Colby Club, 1881-1925, undated (Box 21, Folder 1-2)
      - Economic Problems of Democracy, 1922 (Box 21, Folder 3)
      - Economics, 1894 (Box 21, Folder 4-5)
      - Hadley, James (biographical memoir), 1904 (Box 21, Folder 6)
      - "Pirates of Berlin", Circa 1880's (Box 21, Folder 7)
      - Yale, 1894-1921 (Box 21, Folder 8)
      - Youth's Companion, 1908-1916 (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Hadley, Helen Morris (Mrs. Arthur T.)
    - Appointment Books
      - 1901-1912 (Box 23, Folder 1-5)
      - 1913-1921 (Box 24, Folder 1-4)
      - 1922-1930 (Box 25, Folder 1-3)
    - Correspondence, incoming (mostly in envelopes)
      - 1895-1909 (Box 25, Folder 4-5)
      - 1910-1918 (Box 26, Folder 1-6)
      - 1919-1938, undated (Box 27, Folder 1-2)
      - Publishing rights, 1930-1937 (Box 27, Folder 3)
      - Valentines, 1891-1903 (Box 27, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence, outgoing
      - General, 1891, 1924 (Box 27, Folder 5)
      - Hadley, Arthur T. (husband of Helen), 1899-1915 (Box 27, Folder 6)
      - Family, 1891-1926 (Box 27, Folder 7)
    - Financial, 1890, 1930-1933 (Box 28, Folder 1)
    - Hadley, Arthur T. (notes on), Circa 1937 (Box 28, Folder 2)
    - House expense books, 1891-1938 (Box 28, Folder 3-4)
    - Morris family, 1910 (Box 28, Folder 5)
    - Photographs, Circa 1868-1920s (Box 29, Folder 1-2)
    - Scrapbooks
      Scrapbooks contain clippings, correspondence, photographs, printed ephemera, and other material.
      - 1770-1899 (Box 30, Folder 1-6)
      - 1899-1900 (Box 31, Folder 1-4)
      - 1901-1905 (Box 32, Folder 1-5)
      - 1906-1909 (Box 33, Folder 1-6)
      - 1910-1912 (Box 34, Folder 1-5)
      - 1912-1914 (Box 35, Folder 1-6)
      - 1915-1916 (Box 36, Folder 1-5)
      - 1917-1920 (Box 37, Folder 1-5)
      - 1920-1923 (Box 38, Folder 1-3)
      - 1924-1931 (Box 39, Folder 1-6)
      - 1930 (Box 40, Folder 1-3)
      - Pieces, Undated (Box 40, Folder 4)
      - Trip to Germany, 1907-1908 (Box 41, Folder 1-3)
        - Additional material, includes memorabilia (Box 42, Folder 1-2)
    - Scrapbook ephemera (holidays), 1914-1931 (Box 43, Folder 1-16)
    - Vassar College, 1919-1928 (Box 44, Folder 1)
    - Writings, Saturday Morning Club, 1906-1931 (Box 44, Folder 2)
  - Hadley, Morris
    - Biographical, 1904-1972 (Box 45, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, incoming
      - 1907-1938, undated (Box 45, Folder 2-9)
      - Army (letters of recommendation), 1917 (Box 45, Folder 10)
      - Engagement, 1917-1919 (Box 45, Folder 11)
      - Hadley, Arthur T. (father of Morris), 1906-1918 (Box 45, Folder 12)
      - Hadley, Hamilton (brother of Morris), 1917 (Box 45, Folder 13)
      - Hadley, Katherine Blodgett (mostly in envelopes)
        - 1915-1918 (Box 45, Folder 14-.24)
        - 1918-1943. undated (Box 46, Folder 1-15)
      - Hadley, Laura B. (sister of Morris), 1906-1918 (Box 46, Folder 16)
      - Stokes, Anson Phelps, 1933 (Box 46, Folder 17)
        An interesting letter about his work with Arthur T. Hadley.
    - Correspondence, outgoing
      - Blodgett, Mrs. John W., 1915 (Box 47, Folder 1)
      - Hadley, Arthur T. estate, 1933-1938 (Box 47, Folder 2)
      - Hadley Family (mostly in envelopes)
        - 1905-1918 (Box 47, Folder 3-17)
        - 1918-1938 (Box 48, Folder 1-15)
      - Hadley, Katherine Blodgett (wife of Morris; mostly in envelopes)
        - 1915-1916 (Box 48, Folder 16-20)
        - 1917-1924 (Box 49, Folder 1-19)
        - 1925-1938 (Box 50, Folder 1-4)
    - Education
      - Groton, 1906-1912, 1930 (Box 50, Folder 5-7)
      - Harvard Law School, 1919-1921 (Box 50, Folder 8-9)
      - Yale University, 1912-1916 (Box 50, Folder 10-11)
      - Diplomas, 1916, 1921, 1940 (Box 51, Folder 1)
      - Essays, 1911-1920 (Box 50, Folder 12-13)
    - Engagement calendars (missing years), 1908-1973 (Box 52, Folder 1-3)
    - Far Eastern Trip, 1925 (Box 50, Folder 14-16)
    - Financial
      - Checkbooks, 1912-1920 (Box 50, Folder 17)
      - Publisher contracts, 1951 (Box 50, Folder 18)
    - Military service, 1915-1919,1941 (Box 53, Folder 1-4)
    - Military certificates, 1915-1916, 1946 (Box 54, Folder 1)
    - Orientation of Time and Space (writing), 1929-1955 (Box 55, Folder 1)
    - Photograph album, Circa 1894 (Box 56, Folder 1)
    - Photographs, Circa 1894-1950s (Box 56, Folder 2-8)
  - Hadley, Katherine Blodgett (wife of Morris)
    Morris Hadley's correspondence to Katherine can be found in his outgoing correspondence. Katherine Blodgett Hadley's correspondence to Morris can be found in his incoming correspondence.
    - Correspondence, incoming (wedding), 1919 (Box 57, Folder 1-3)
    - Correspondence, outgoing (mostly in envelopes)
      - Hadley, Arthur T. and Helen Morris Hadley, 1918-1933 (Box 57, Folder 4-7)
      - Hadley, Helen Morris, 1933-1939 (Box 57, Folder 8-9)
    - Photographs, 1904-1933 (Box 57, Folder 10)
    - Scrapbook, 1913-1915 (Box 57, Folder 11-19)
    - Vassar College
      - Euthenics, 1928 (Box 57, Folder 20)
        Includes interesting autobigraphical sketches of Morris and Katherine.
      - Student paper, Circa 1919 (Box 57, Folder 21)
    - Wedding, 1919 (Box 57, Folder 22)
  - Hadley Family
    - House (93 Whitney Avenue), Circa 1880s-1890s (Box 58, Folder 1)
    - Photograph Albums
      - 1904-1908 (Box 59, Folder 1-4)
      - 1909-1910 (Box 60, Folder 1-2)
      - 1910-1911 (Box 61, Folder 1-2)
      - 1912-1913 (Box 62, Folder 1-2)
      - 1913-1914 (Box 63, Folder 1-2)
      - 1915-1916 (Box 64, Folder 1-2)
      - 1917-1919 (Box 65, Folder 1-2)
      - 1920-1925 (Box 66, Folder 1-2)
      - 1930-1936 (Box 67, Folder 1)
      - Undated (Box 67, Folder 2)
      - Undated (Box 68, Folder 1)
    - Photographs
      - General
        - Circa 1870s-1908 (Box 68, Folder 2)
        - Undated (Box 68, Folder 3)
      - House (93 Whitney Avenue), Circa 1880s, 1890s (Box 68, Folder 4)
  - Magill Family, 1892, undated (Box 68, Folder 5)
- Additional material, 1729-1950; Accession 2013-M-043; 2.25; (5 boxes)
  This accession consists of correspondence of Arthur Twining Hadley compiled by Morris Hadley for his biography of Arthur Twining Hadley. There is also additional material consisting of manuscript notes for the biography and notes related to the publication of James Hadley's diary.
  - Arthur Twining Hadley correspondence, with notes
    - Property deed and correspondence prior to April 23, 1856, 1729, 1856 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - 1856-1871, 1941 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - 1872-1876, 1899, 1936 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - 1871, 1941 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - 1877-1879, 1941 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - 1878-1888 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - 1879, undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
      Includes correspondence relating to the deaths and executorship of the estates of Mary and Julia Twining.
    - 1879, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - 1880 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - 1881 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - 1882 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - 1883 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - 1884 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - 1885, circa 1940 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - 1886 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - 1885, 1887, 1924 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - 1888 (Box 2, Folder 1)